Most of us go through life trying to do our best at whatever we do, whether it's our job, family, school or anything else.
这一辈子，不管是我们的工作事务、家庭琐事、学校任务，或是其他，我们大都尽己所能，做到最好，
I feel that way. I try my best.
我这么想，也这么做。
But some time ago, I came to a realization
但是一段时间以前，我意识到，
that I wasn't getting much better at the things I cared most about,
我在我最在乎的事情上并没有进步，
whether it was being a husband or a friend or a professional or teammate, and I wasn't improving much at those things
不管是作为丈夫或是朋友，或是专家，或者队友。
even though I was spending a lot of time
即使我在这些事上花费了大量时间，
working hard at them.
做了很多努力，我却没有太多进步。
I've since realized from conversations I've had and from research
我之后在与他人的谈话和研究中意识到，
that this stagnation, despite hard work,
这种白白耗费努力的停滞，
turns out to be pretty common.
原来非常普遍。
So I'd like to share with you some insights into why that is
所以我想与大家分享一些，
and what we can all do about it.
关于它为何发生和如何应对的见解。
What I've learned is that the most effective people and teams in any domain
我所了解的是，无论哪个领域，最高效的个人和团队，
do something we can all emulate.
都会做一件我们可以效仿的事情：
They go through life deliberately alternating between two zones:
生活中，他们有意识的在两个区域转换：
the learning zone and the performance zone.
学习区和展现区。
The learning zone is when our goal is to improve.
在学习区，我们希冀进步，
Then we do activities designed for improvement,
我们为了进步而计划行为，
concentrating on what we haven't mastered yet,
将精力集中在那些我们还没有掌握的东西上，
which means we have to expect to make mistakes,
我们意识到自己会犯错，
knowing that we will learn from them.
并且知道我们会从中汲取什么教训。
That is very different from what we do when we're in our performance zone,
这和我们在展现区做的完全不同，
which is when our goal is to do something as best as we can, to execute.
在展现区我们的目标是做到最好，去执行，
Then we concentrate on what we have already mastered
我们在已经掌握的东西上集中精力，
and we try to minimize mistakes.
并尽力把错误缩小。
Both of these zones should be part of our lives,
这两个区域都应是我们生活的一部分，
but being clear about when we want to be in each of them,
但是在进入区域之前，想清楚我们进的是哪个区，
with what goal, focus and expectations,
我们的目标是什么、精力放在哪、有什么样的期望，
helps us better perform and better improve.
这会帮助我们更好的提升或表现
The performance zone maximizes our immediate performance,
在展现区将展现最大化，
while the learning zone maximizes our growth
在学习区将进步最大化
and our future performance.
并在未来的展现中将其表现。
The reason many of us don't improve much despite our hard work
我们努力工作却没有太多进步的原因，
is that we tend to spend almost all of our time in the performance zone.
是我们往往将时间都花在了展现区里。
This hinders our growth,
这阻碍着我们的进步，
and ironically, over the long term, also our performance.
更讽刺的是，长久来看，这也影响着我们的展现。
So what does the learning zone look like?
那学习区是什么样的呢？
Take Demosthenes, a political leader and the greatest orator and lawyer in ancient Greece.
看看古希腊的政治领导者、最伟大的演说家、律师，狄摩西尼吧。
To become great, he didn't spend all his time just being an orator or a lawyer,
为了成就伟大，他没有把所有时间花费在仅仅作为演说家或者律师上--
which would be his performance zone.
也就是他展现区的一部分。
But instead, he did activities designed for improvement.
反而，他为了进步规划行为，
Of course, he studied a lot.
是的，他大量地学习。
He studied law and philosophy with guidance from mentors,
他不仅在导师的帮助下学习法律和哲学，
but he also realized that being a lawyer involved persuading other people,
他还意识到了律师的职责包括说服他人，
so he also studied great speeches and acting.
所以他研习了许多伟大的演说和表演。
To get rid of an odd habit he had of involuntarily lifting his shoulder,
为了戒掉他不自主抬胳膊的习惯，
he practiced his speeches in front of a mirror,
他在一面镜子前练习演说，
and he suspended a sword from the ceiling
并将一把剑吊在房梁上，
so that if he raised his shoulder,
这样如果他抬起了肩膀，
it would hurt.
剑就会刺痛他。
(Laughter)
（笑声）
To speak more clearly despite a lisp,
为了发音清晰，
he went through his speeches with stones in his mouth.
他在演说时嘴里含着石头。
He built an underground room
他还建造了一个地下室，
where he could practice without interruptions
这样他在练习的时候就不会被打扰，
and not disturb other people.
也不会打扰到别人。
And since courts at the time were very noisy,
因为那时候的法庭很嘈杂，
he also practiced by the ocean,
对此他在海边练习，
projecting his voice above the roar of the waves.
保证声音在海浪的咆哮中清晰可听。
His activities in the learning zone
他在学习区所做的行为，
were very different from his activities in court, his performance zone.
和他在法庭上的行为，也就是他展现区的行为，远远不同。
In the learning zone,
在学习区，
he did what Dr. Anders Ericsson calls deliberate practice.
安德斯•埃里克森博士称这种行为为“有意练习”，
This involves breaking down abilities into component skills,
这种练习包括了将能力转化为所需技能，
being clear about what subskill we're working to improve,
对我们需要提升什么非主要技能非常清楚，
like keeping our shoulders down,
就像狄摩西尼将肩膀放低，
giving full concentration to a high level of challenge
还有将精力集中在我们舒适区之外、
outside our comfort zone,
更高一级的挑战，
just beyond what we can currently do,
做超越我们现在正做的事，
using frequent feedback with repetition and adjustments,
在重复和调整中得到反馈，
and ideally engaging the guidance of a skilled coach,
最好能得到熟练者的指导，
because activities designed for improvement are domain-specific,
因为为了进步而设定行为是件很内行的事。
and great teachers and coaches know what those activities are
好的老师和教练了解什么行为能带来进步，
and can also give us expert feedback.
也能给我们专业的反馈。
It is this type of practice in the learning zone
学习区中，给我们带来很大的进步的，
which leads to substantial improvement, not just time on task performing.
正是这样的练习，而不是单纯的完成任务。
For example, research shows that after the first couple of years working in a profession,
例如，研究表明，在某一行业最初工作的几年，
performance usually plateaus.
展现的进步会停滞。
This has been shown to be true in teaching, general medicine, nursing and other fields,
这已经在教育、普通内科、护理和其他领域都到了印证，
and it happens because once we think we have become good enough, adequate,
我们一旦认为自己足够好、足够适合工作，而停止学习，
then we stop spending time in the learning zone.
它就会发生在我们身上。
We focus all our time on just doing our job,
我们仅是把时间花费在完成工作上，
performing,
也就是展现，
which turns out not to be a great way to improve.
这决不是进步的好方法。
But the people who continue to spend time in the learning zone
而那些继续在学习区花费时间的人，
do continue to always improve.
确实在不停进步。
The best salespeople at least once a week
最好的推销员至少每周一次，
do activities with the goal of improvement.
进行自我提高的活动。
They read to extend their knowledge,
他们通过阅读拓展知识，
consult with colleagues or domain experts,
与同事或行业专家交换意见，
try out new strategies, solicit feedback and reflect.
尝试新的策略、征集反馈并以此作出反应。
The best chess players
最好的国际象棋棋手，
spend a lot of time not playing games of chess,
并没有将大部分时间花在他们的表现区——
which would be their performance zone,
也就是下象棋上，
but trying to predict the moves grand masters made and analyzing them.
而是努力去预测象棋大师的着子并加以分析。
Each of us has probably spent many, many, many hours
我们在电脑打字上，
typing on a computer
花费了很多时间
without getting faster,
却没有打得更快，
but if we spent 10 to 20 minutes each day
但是我们如果每天都能抽出10-20分钟，
fully concentrating on typing 10 to 20 percent faster
全神贯注地提升打字速度，
than our current reliable speed,
就比平常快上10%-20%，
we would get faster,
我们打字的速度就会提升，
especially if we also identified what mistakes we're making
尤其是我们还找出了我们常犯的错，
and practiced typing those words.
并且还加以纠正练习。
That's deliberate practice.
这就是“有意练习”。
In what other parts of our lives,
打字毕竟不是主业，
perhaps that we care more about,
我们有其他更在乎的领域，
are we working hard but not improving much
那些我们努力过，但是提升甚少的领域，
because we're always in the performance zone?
这是因为我们总停留在展现区吗？
Now, this is not to say that the performance zone has no value.
这并不意味展现区毫无价值，
It very much does.
它非常有价值。
When I needed a knee surgery, I didn't tell the surgeon,
我不会告诉我膝盖手术的主治医生：
"Poke around in there and focus on what you don't know."
“随便弄吧，把膝盖当作你的教具，”
(Laughter)
（笑声）
"We'll learn from your mistakes!"
“你犯错了我们都会吸取教训的！”
I looked for a surgeon who I felt would do a good job,
我会找一个我认为能做好手术的外科医生，
and I wanted her to do a good job.
我也想让她顺利完成手术。
Being in the performance zone
在展现区做事，
allows us to get things done as best as we can.
要求我们做到最好。
It can also be motivating,
这本身就是一种鞭策，
and it provides us with information to identify what to focus on next
它也能让我们知道，当我们回到学习区的时候，
when we go back to the learning zone.
我们应当注意什么。
So the way to high performance
通往高水平展现的路，
is to alternate between the learning zone and the performance zone,
就是在学习区、表现区间来回转换的路，
purposefully building our skills in the learning zone,
我们有目的地在学习区积攒技能，
then applying those skills in the performance zone.
然后将其应用于展现区。
When Beyoncé is on tour,
当碧昂斯举办巡回演唱会时，
during the concert, she's in her performance zone,
演唱会，就是她的展现区，
but every night when she gets back to the hotel room,
但是当她每晚回到酒店房间时，
she goes right back into her learning zone.
她就径直地回到了她的学习区。
She watches a video of the show that just ended.
她会观看刚刚结束的演出的录像。
She identifies opportunities for improvement, for herself, her dancers and her camera staff.
为她自己、舞者、摄像组寻求进步的突破口。
And the next morning,
第二天早上，
everyone receives pages of notes with what to adjust,
每个人都会收到几页笔记，上面写着
which they then work on during the day before the next performance.
他们需要在下次演出前需要调整的问题。
It's a spiral to ever-increasing capabilities,
提高能力是一个螺旋上升的过程，
but we need to know when we seek to learn, and when we seek to perform,
但是我们得知道何时学习、何时表现，
and while we want to spend time doing both,
当想两者兼顾时，
the more time we spend in the learning zone, the more we'll improve.
想要进步，就要多花时间在学习区上。
So how can we spend more time in the learning zone?
那我们如何将更多时间用在学习区上呢？
First, we must believe and understand that we can improve,
首先，坚定我们一定会进步的信念，
what we call a growth mindset.
我们叫它“成长思维”。
Second, we must want to improve at that particular skill.
其次，成长目标必须明确。
There has to be a purpose we care about,
时间、精力有限，
because it takes time and effort.
它们必须花费在我们在乎的目标上。
Third, we must have an idea about how to improve,
第三，我们必须要知道如何提高，
what we can do to improve,
怎样提高，
not how I used to practice the guitar as a teenager,
不能像小时候学吉他，
performing songs over and over again,
一遍遍重复单调的歌曲，
but doing deliberate practice.
而是做一些有意的练习。
And fourth, we must be in a low-stakes situation,
第四，保证低风险，
because if mistakes are to be expected,
因为犯错在意料之中，
then the consequence of making them must not be catastrophic,
其后果必不能不堪设想，
or even very significant.
哪怕是有一点严重都不行。
A tightrope walker doesn't practice new tricks without a net underneath,
没有拦网，走钢索的人不会去训练新技巧，
and an athlete wouldn't set out to first try a new move during a championship match.
在大赛上，运动员也不会去开发新的动作。
One reason that in our lives we spend so much time in the performance zone
我们之所以在展现区耗费大量时间，
is that our environments often are, unnecessarily, high stakes.
是因为我们通常不必要地将环境置于高风险的状态。
We create social risks for one another,
我们给彼此制造了社会风险，
even in schools which are supposed to be all about learning,
即使在我们一切都为了学习的学校里，
and I'm not talking about standardized tests.
我没有在说标准化考试，
I mean that every minute of every day,
我说的是学生每时每刻、
many students in elementary schools through colleges
从小学到大学，
feel that if they make a mistake, others will think less of them.
都会觉得别人会因为他们犯错而轻视他们。
No wonder they're always stressed out
难怪学生一直紧张兮兮，
and not taking the risks necessary for learning.
不愿为学习而冒必要的风险。
But they learn that mistakes are undesirable
老师、家长对正确答案趋之若鹜的态度，
inadvertently
无意中
when teachers or parents are eager to hear just correct answers
让学生抗拒犯错，
and reject mistakes rather than welcome and examine them to learn from them,
而不是勇于试错、检视过错、并从中吸取教训，
or when we look for narrow responses
我们也只想要“标准答案”，
rather than encourage more exploratory thinking that we can all learn from.
而不是激励学生去进行大有裨益的开拓性思考。
When all homework or student work has a number or a letter on it,
一旦学生的作业、作品，都会被评定等级、标上分数，
and counts towards a final grade,
最后被记入期末成绩，
rather than being used for practice, mistakes, feedback and revision,
它们就起不到练习、试错、反馈、修正的作用了，
we send the message that school is a performance zone.
我们让孩子误认为学校是展现区。
The same is true in our workplaces.
职场中也同样如此。
In the companies I consult with, I often see flawless execution cultures
那些咨询我的公司，经常执行无缺陷企业文化，
which leaders foster to encourage great work.
领导们努力于激励工作。
But that leads employees to stay within what they know
但这会让员工停留在自己已知的领域，
and not try new things,
固步自封，
so companies struggle to innovate and improve,
公司因此很难创新、进步，
and they fall behind.
从而落了下风。
We can create more spaces for growth
我们可以通过交流，
by starting conversations with one another
为彼此开创进步的空间，
about when we want to be in each zone.
可以让行为各属所区的空间。
What do we want to get better at and how?
何处改进？如何改进？
And when do we want to execute and minimize mistakes?
何时决策？怎样控损？
That way, we gain clarity about what success is,
何为成功，何时、以何种方法去支持对方，
when, and how to best support one another.
由此在我们眼前清晰展现。
But what if we find ourselves in a chronic high-stakes setting
那要是我们发现自己长期都在高风险状态下，
and we feel we can't start those conversations yet?
并且无法开展这样的交流怎么办？
Then here are three things that we can still do as individuals.
作为个人，我们仍可以做这下面三点：
First, we can create low-stakes islands in an otherwise high-stakes sea.
首先，我们可以在高风险的汪洋中开辟一个低风险的小岛，
These are spaces where mistakes have little consequence.
在这里，错误的后果不会太严重，
For example, we might find a mentor or a trusted colleague
比如，我们可以找一个导师，或是可信的同事，
with whom we can exchange ideas or have vulnerable conversations
和他们分享想法，或是接受批评，
or even role-play.
甚至角色代入都行。
Or we can ask for feedback-oriented meetings as projects progress.
或者是随着项目的进展，举办反馈向会议。
Or we can set aside time to read or watch videos or take online courses.
我们也可以抽出时间去阅读相关书籍、看视频或是参加在线课程。
Those are just some examples.
这只是几个例子。
Second, we can execute and perform as we're expected,
其次，我们可以遵循着预期去执行，
but then reflect on what we could do better next time,
但将精力集中于如何在下次做的更好，
like Beyoncé does,
就像碧昂斯，
and we can observe and emulate experts.
我们可以观察并模仿专家所做。
The observation, reflection and adjustment is a learning zone.
这些观察、映射和调整属于学习区。
And finally, we can lead
最终，我们可以通过和他人分享希冀在何处取得进步，
and lower the stakes for others by sharing what we want to get better at,
通过询问未知的问题，
by asking questions about what we don't know,
通过征求反馈，
by soliciting feedback and by sharing our mistakes
通过分享我们曾经犯过的错，和从中汲取的教训，
and what we've learned from them,
为彼此营造一个低风险的状态，
so that others can feel safe to do the same.
这样他人也会安心地做同样的事。
Real confidence is about modeling ongoing learning.
进步的奥秘就在规范现行的学习行为中。
What if, instead of spending our lives doing, doing, doing,
如果，我们没有把时间耗费在
performing, performing, performing,
做事、表现、输出上，
we spent more time exploring,
而是更多地去探索、
asking,
询问、
listening,
倾听、
experimenting, reflecting,
实践、斟酌、
striving and becoming?
拼命去成为想成为的人，会怎么样？
What if we each always had something we were working to improve?
如果我们每个人，都有某些事情让我们可为之努力，从而提高呢？
What if we created more low-stakes islands and waters?
如果我们可以找到，或者创造出更多的低风险地带呢？
And what if we got clear, within ourselves and with our teammates,
那如果我们对于自身和团队成员，
about when we seek to learn and when we seek to perform,
何时需要学习，何时需要表现非常清楚呢？
so that our efforts can become more consequential,
做到这些，我们的努力会得到更多回报，
our improvement never-ending
我们的进步会一往直前，
and our best even better?
我们的工作会锦上添花。
Thank you.
谢谢大家。